A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Office of the Vice President, Office Files of Francis X. Sutton FA568
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation History Project, Subject Files, 1949-1985; VII
  - Overseas Development Program -- Notes Re: Economic Development, 1984 (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Overseas Development Program -- Reports, Project Charts, May 1955 Docket Re: Division History, Activities, Operating Methods, 1952-1955 (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - Overseas Development Program -- Reports to Trustees and Program Summary, 1954-1956 (Box 74, Folder 11)
  - Overseas Development Program -- Program Docket for Board of Trustees Meeting, 1957 June 21-22 (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - Overseas Development Program -- Program Docket for Board of Trustees Meeting, 1958 (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - Overseas Development Program -- Report, "Africa Program, 1957-1958", 1958 July 3 (Box 74, Folder 14)
  - Overseas Development Program -- Program Dockets for Board of Trustees Meetings, 1959-1961 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Personnel Directory, 1963 November 1 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Personnel Flow Charts, 1981 January 1 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Population -- Report, "The Ford Foundation's Activities in Population", 1968 August (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Social Science Conference (Feb 10-11, 1972) -- Agenda, List of Participants, Minutes, Reflections, 1971-1972 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Social Science Research Council - American Council of Learned Societies (SSRC-ACLS) Grants/Joint Committees -- Memoranda, Notes, Grant Recommendations, 1970-1982 (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - Sutton -- Foundation History Text -- Introduction, 1984 (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - Sutton -- Foundation History Text -- Part 1, circa 1984-1985 (Box 75, Folder 8)
  - Sutton -- Foundation History Text -- Africa, Latin America and Regional Approaches, 1985 July 1 (Box 75, Folder 9)
  - Sutton -- Foundation History Text -- The Ford Foundation in the Middle East and Africa, 1984 December 10 (Box 75, Folder 10)
  - Sutton -- Foundation History Text -- The Ford Foundation in Nepal, 1985 March 28 (Box 75, Folder 11)
  - Sutton -- Foundation History Text -- The Ford Foundation in Turkey, 1985 April 24 (Box 75, Folder 12)
  - Sutton -- Foundation History Text -- Overseas Development Part II -- The Initial Shaping of Policy, 1984 August 30 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Sutton -- Foundation History Text -- Working Out Overseas Development to 1966 -- The Guiding Motivations and Strategies, 1985 June 18 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Sutton -- Foundation History Text -- Nation Building: Social Transformation and Cultural Unity, circa 1984-1985 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Sutton -- Foundation History Text -- Tables and Charts, undated (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Sutton -- Foundation History Text -- "From Cold War to Cultural Development: The International Cultural Activities of the Ford Foundation, 1950-1982" by Kathleen D. McCarthy, 1985 April (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Sutton -- Foundation History Text -- "The Ford Foundation's Population Programs in India, Pakistan and Bangladesh, 1959-1981" by Kathleen D. McCarthy, circa 1985 (Box 76, Folder 6)
- Researcher Files, 1983-2002, bulk 1985-1987; 1985-1987; VIII
  The six "Researcher" files document Dr. Sutton's use of the Ford Foundation Archives. They record the collections he consulted and the documents he requested while working on his history of the Foundation's international activities, as well as reference copies of some of the chapters he wrote. The series also includes correspondence between Dr. Sutton and Ann Newhall, the Foundation's archivist, regarding his citation of archival materials within the history text.
  The files are arranged by box number according to the original Records Management boxes from which they were pulled, and then chronologically.
  - Archive Use Re: History of Ford Foundation, 1983-1985 (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Citation Check Re: Sutton Manuscript, "American Philanthropy in Educational and Cultural Exchange with the People's Republic of China" (1 of 3), 1985-1987 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Citation Check Re: History of the Ford Foundation International Division Part I (2 of 3), 1986-1987 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Citation Check re: Sutton Manuscript, "International Philanthropy in a Large Foundation" (3 of 3), 1987 (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - Research on Dwight Macdonald for Book Introduction (1 of 2), 1987 (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Research on Ford Foundation International Work and Grants, Records of Individuals (2 of 2), 2001-2002 (Box 76, Folder 12)
- Visual Materials, 1951-1985; IX
  Separated Materials
  Several of the files within this series were separated from the Program and Ford Foundation History Project Files series.
  This series contains photographs of Ford Foundation staff, officers, and trustees, program work abroad, field offices and international visits. There is also one sheet of slides of miscellaneous museum artifacts, artwork, and antiques.
  Alphabetical arrangement.
  - Africa Mission II -- Francis X. Sutton, Alfred C. Wolf, Melvin J. Fox (separated from Trip Files--Africa Mission II), circa 1957 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- New Delhi Staff (separated from report "A Brief Note on the Ford Foundation's Current Program in India"), 1985 September (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Center for Advanced Studies in the Behavioral Sciences Reception, 1955 January 7 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Inventory of Photographs in the Ford Foundation History File and List of Ford Foundation Negatives, circa 1958-1985 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Foundation Images -- Field Offices, Staff Working Abroad, Agriculture, International Universities, Rural Development and Family Planning Programs, 1965-1967 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Photographs from F. Champion Ward -- International Visits including Beirut, circa 1956 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Staff/Officer/Trustee Photographs, A-E, circa 1954-1974 (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Staff/Officer/Trustee Photographs, F-H, circa 1951-1970 (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Staff/Officer/Trustee Photographs. K-N, undated (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Staff/Officer/Trustee Photographs. P-Z, circa 1961-1968 (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - Slides -- Artwork, undated (Box 77, Folder 11)